Charlie Nelms papers, 1967-2016 C701
Indiana University Archives
Charlie Nelms papers
1967-2016
1988-2013
Indiana University Archives
Nelms, Charlie, 1946-
C701
8 cubic feet
Charlie Nelms (b. 1946) served in executive leadership roles for the Indiana University system for a total of twenty-four years between 1978 and 2007. This collection spans Nelms' personal life and professional career in university administration at IU and other institutions. The collection includes writings, correspondence, publications and reports, and ephemera.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research. Advance notice required for access to collection.
Biographical Note
Charlie Nelms was born in 1946 in Crawfordsville, Arkansas. His family members were cotton subsistence farmers and rural community organizers, many of whom moved to Midwestern cities like Chicago and Flint during the post-war second great migration. Nelms earned his B.S. in chemistry and agronomy from University of Arkansas at Pine Bluff in 1968. He then attended Indiana University, where he earned his M.S. in higher education and student affairs in 1971 and his Ed.D. in higher education administration in 1977.
After working in administration at Earlham College and University of Arkansas at Pine Bluff, Nelms worked at Indiana University Northwest as Associate Dean for Academic Affairs and Assistant Professor of Education from 1978-1984. Following a period of employment as Vice President for Student Services at Sinclair Community College (Dayton, Ohio), Nelms returned to the IU regional system as Chancellor and Professor of Education at Indiana University East in 1987. He served in this role from 1987-1994. He left Indiana in 1994 to become Chancellor and Professor of Education at University of Michigan-Flint, a position he served until 1998. Nelms returned to Indiana in 1998 as a member of IU's executive leadership team. He served as Vice President for Institutional Development and Student Affairs and Professor of Higher Education Administration at IU (Bloomington campus) from 1998-2007. In total, Nelms served in higher administration for the Indiana University system for twenty-four years.
In 2007 Nelms became Chancellor at North Carolina Central University (NCCU), a public historically black university. He retired from NCCU in 2012. Since then, Nelms has focused on research and consulting primarily for historically black colleges and universities (HBCUs). Since 2014 he has been a Senior Fellow for the Division of Academic Leadership & Change, American Association of State Colleges & Universities (AASCU) and Senior Consultant for AGB Consulting in Washington, D.C. In 2015 he established Nelms & Associates, a higher education consulting firm that specializes in strategic planning and communications, enrollment management, and diversity and inclusion.
Nelms has written prolifically about education and race throughout his career. In 2011 he published A Call to Action: Strengthening America's Historically Black Colleges and Universities after participating in a series of symposiums on the topic at NCCU. He has been a columnist for the Huffington Post since 2012, where he blogs about family, leadership, higher education, and civil rights. His first memoir publication was Lessons Taught, Lessons Learned (Mansfield, Ohio: Bookmasters) in 2004. In 2019, Indiana University Press published Nelms' From Cotton Fields to University Leadership: All Eyes on Charlie, A Memoir. The book details his upbringing in the Deep South, his educational journey, and his experiences as a black administrator in predominantly white universities.
Nelms has been granted honorary degrees from Earlham College (1993), University of Arkansas at Pine Bluff (2001), and Indiana University (2019). He has been awarded The President's Medal from the University of Michigan (1996), the Distinguished Alumni Service Award from Indiana University (1996), the City of Bloomington Dr. Martin Luther King Jr. Legacy Award (2007), the U.S. Department of Education MLK Drum Major for Service Award (2012), and the Distinguished Leadership Award from the American Association of Blacks in Higher Education (2013), among other distinctions.
Arrangement
Collection is arranged into seven series: Speeches, Indiana University East, Indiana University Bloomington, Other Institutions, Professional Activities, Personal, and Audiovisual.
Scope and Content Note
This collection contains the personal papers of Charlie Nelms in seven series.
The Speeches series spans 1967-2016 and is arranged chronologically. It includes transcripts, notes, and documents from Nelms' public speaking engagements. This includes Nelms' keynote speeches at community events and institutions, churches and charities, and professional conferences. Many of these speeches took place in the communities surrounding universities where Nelms worked.
The Indiana University East series spans 1987-1995 and is arranged alphabetically. This series contains files from Nelms' tenure as Chancellor and Professor of Education at IU East in Richmond, Indiana. This includes official reports, correspondence, subject files, mementos, and media clippings. Relevant topics include enrollment strategies for black students, diversity, and multiculturalism. This series also includes a photo album documenting a 1991 trip Nelms made to Koryo Junior High School in Kushiro, Hokkaido, Japan.
The Indiana University Bloomington series spans 1992-2007 and is arranged alphabetically. This series contains files from Nelms' tenure as Vice President for Institutional Development and Student Affairs at IU. It includes correspondence, reports, and subject files. Relevant topics include the Office of Sustainability 20/20 Plan, Neal-Marshall Black Cultural Center, and student retention and diversity.
The Other Institutions series spans 1973-2016 and is arranged alphabetically. It covers Nelms' professional engagement with other, mostly academic, institutions. Contents include files from Nelms' tenure at Indiana University Northwest, Sinclair Community College, as well as his graduate education at Indiana University. Of special interest are files from Nelms' tenure as Chancellor at North Carolina Central University. The series also includes issues of NCCU Now, a North Carolina Central University publication.
The Professional Activities series spans 1981-2017 and is arranged alphabetically. This series covers Nelms' professional activities with regional and national organizations, commissions, and projects. Files include awards, event programs, correspondence, notes and remarks, and publications. Significant portions of this series concern Nelms' work with historically black colleges and universities (HBCU's). Significant organizations include the American Association of State Colleges and Universities (AASCU), American Council on Education (ACE), and Middle States Association (MSA).
The Personal series spans 1971-2016 and is arranged chronologically. This series contains files related to Nelms' educational background, family, and research. It includes family correspondence, publications, mementos such as buttons and badges, and media clippings. Some of the publications in this series are authored by Nelms. One box in this series contains Nelms' planners and contacts, 1979-1996.
The Audiovisual series contains audiovisual material spanning 1979-2011 and is arranged alphabetically by title. This includes videotapes, DVDs, audio cassettes, and one vinyl 45 RPM record. Titles include lectures and educational programs.
Related Material
Related photographs may be available in the University Archives Photographs Database.
Separated Material
Materials from Charlie Nelms' tenure at University of Michigan-Flint have been separated to be sent to the Genesee Historical Collections Center, a division of the University of Michigan-Flint Thompson Library.
Acquisition Information
Accession: 2018-091
Provenance
Transferred by Charlie Nelms to the University Archives, 2018.
- Speeches, 1967-2016
  Scope and Content Note
  Contains transcripts, notes, and documents from Nelms' public speaking engagements, including keynote speeches at community events and institutions, churches and charities, and professional conferences.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged chronologically
  - Charlie Nelms curriculum vitae and list of speeches, 1994-2016 (Box 1)
  - Speeches and writings, 1967-1968 (Box 1)
  - Remarks, 1979-1998 (Box 1)
  - Speeches, circa 1981 (Box 1)
  - Loose speeches, 1980-1983 (Box 1)
  - Teaching Decision Making Skills, Thornton Community College, February 28, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Events, 1982-2008 (Box 1)
  - Annual dinner remarks, Urban League, 1982 (Box 1)
  - Speeches, 1982 (Box 1)
  - Speeches, 1983-1984 (Box 1)
  - Mechanisms of Networking and Implementation, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Martin Luther King Celebration, 1991 (Box 1)
  - First Lecture, P510, September 13, 1982 (Box 1)
  - Prerequisites for Leadership, Phi Theta Kappa induction ceremony, May 25, 1984 (Box 1)
  - Prerequisites for Leadership, Phi Delta Kappa induction ceremony, November 24, 1987 (Box 1)
  - The New Slavery, 1988 (Box 1)
  - Townsend Community Center Membership Program, January 9, 1988 (Box 1)
  - Second Baptist Church (Bloomington) Black History Program, February 12, 1988 (Box 1)
  - A Personal Honor Code, First English Lutheran Church, April 17, 1988 (Box 1)
  - Promises and Prospects in Education, Delta Kappa Gamma, May 9, 1988 (Box 1)
  - Regional Campus Perspective Speech, June 17, 1988 (Box 1)
  - Man in the Mirror, St. Timothy Community Church Men's Day, Gary, Indiana, June 19, 1988; 2 Folders (Box 1)
  - INROADS Regional Training Institute, June 30, 1988 (Box 1)
  - Re-emerging Role of Historically Black Colleges-The Role of Alumni, University of Arkansas at Pine Bluff Alumni Meeting in Cincinnati, June 30, 1988 (Box 1)
  - Prerequisites for Leadership, New Castle Chrysler High School, November 15, 1988 (Box 1)
  - Speech file, 1989-1990 (Box 1)
  - What Is Your Dream? MLK Birthday Celebration, January 15, 1989 (Box 1)
  - New Castle Speech, January 26, 1989 (Box 1)
  - Leadership Wayne County Presentation, January 30, 1989 (Box 1)
  - Principles of Parenting, Townsend Community Center, March 11, 1989 (Box 1)
  - American Business Women's Association remarks, May 8, 1989 (Box 1)
  - Noon Kiwanis speech, June 2, 1989 (Box 1)
  - All Campus Luncheon Speech, September 15, 1989 (Box 1)
  - I-CASE Remarks, October 12, 1989 (Box 1)
  - Speech ideas, 1990-1993 (Box 1)
  - Speech ideas, 1990-1996 (Box 1)
  - The New Majority: Student Needs in the 21st Century, January 11, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Symposium, Indiana University Bloomington, January 22, 1990 (Box 1)
  - The Prerequisites for African American Leadership for the 1990's and Beyond: Remarks to the Editorial Board of The Negro Educational Review, April 13-14, 1990 (Box 1)
  - August Eberle Memorial Remarks, November 16, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Earlham Convocation, January 27, 1991 (Box 1)
  - Comments to Paul Barton-Kriese's Class, January 30, 1991 (Box 1)
  - Kiwanis speech, June 27, 1991 (Box 1)
  - Prerequisites for Personal and Organizational Renewal, June 28, 1991 (Box 1)
  - Overcoming the Odds, Vaile School Comments, January 17, 1992 (Box 1)
  - Whitewater College Programs, Inc., March 19, 1992 (Box 1)
  - Prerequisites for Leadership: LEAD Class, April 11, 1992 (Box 1)
  - University Skills for Success, April 16, 1992 (Box 1)
  - Rotary comments, May 19, 1992 (Box 1)
  - Diversity: Beyond the Jargon, September 24, 1992 (Box 1)
  - Back to School Celebration, Robinson Community AME Church, October 8, 1992 (Box 1)
  - Junior Achievement remarks, October 14, 1992 (Box 1)
  - McNair National Student Conference, November 6-8, 1992 (Box 1)
  - The Fruit of the Spirit, Christian Men's Fellowship, December 15, 1992 (Box 1)
  - Bridging the Gap Between High School and College, Otterbein College, February 25, 1993 (Box 1)
  - Strategies for Halting the Brain Drain, Rural-Urban Banquet, March 19, 1993 (Box 1)
  - Talk with "Moving On" Participants, August 13, 1993 (Box 1)
  - Racial Justice, St. Mary's, October 23, 1993 (Box 1)
  - Rotary remarks, October 26, 1993 (Box 1)
  - Pro and Con Program, Indiana University Bloomington, November 1, 1993 (Box 1)
  - Presentation to Ethics Class, February 2, 1994 (Box 1)
  - Richmond Christian School, March 11, 1994 (Box 1)
  - A New Agenda for a New Era, October 1, 1994 (Box 1)
  - Gandhi March, October 2, 1994 (Box 1)
  - Prerequisites for Leadership, October 25, 1994 (Box 1)
  - Foss Avenue Christian School, October 28, 1994 (Box 1)
  - Kiwanis Club of Flint Speech, December 1, 1994 (Box 1)
  - Flint Rotary Club Speech, December 2, 1994 (Box 1)
  - Dare to Dream Children's Program, January 14, 1995 (Box 1)
  - Sigma Pi Phi Fraternity Speech, January 21, 1995 (Box 1)
  - Minority Business Breakfast, January 31, 1995 (Box 1)
  - Vermont Christian Church, February 5, 1995 (Box 1)
  - Gear Board Meeting, February 10, 1995 (Box 1)
  - League of Women Voters, Flint Public Library, February 13, 1995 (Box 1)
  - Mott Adult High School-Bryant Center, Black History Program Speech, February 16, 1995 (Box 1)
  - Alternatives for Children and Families, February 24, 1995 (Box 1)
  - Pilgrim Missionary Baptist Church Annual Banquet, February 25, 1995 (Box 1)
  - Christ the Liberator Presbyterian Church, March 19, 1995 (Box 1)
  - EDU 331 Urban Education Speech, April 11, 1995 (Box 1)
  - 1995 Leadership Retreat, April 22, 1995 (Box 1)
  - Flint Chapter of the University of Arkansas at Pine Bluff, April 29, 1995 (Box 1)
  - Flint Neighborhood Coalition 13th Annual Awards Dinner, May 5, 1995 (Box 1)
  - American Red Cross Annual Dinner, May 17, 1995 (Box 1)
  - CSR Project, Building a Collaborative Community, May 17, 1995 (Box 1)
  - The Urban League of Flint 13th Annual Salute to Black Scholars, May 22, 1995 (Box 1)
  - Flint Area Jazz Legends, June 3, 1995 (Box 1)
  - Northwestern High School, September 18, 1995 (Box 1)
  - Enhancing Minority Attainment Conference Panel Discussion, Indiana University Kokomo, September 30, 1995 (Box 1)
  - First Annual College Emphasis Week, February, 1996 (Box 1)
  - African American History-A Celebration of Diversity, Dye Elementary School, February 2, 1996 (Box 1)
  - The Crisis of Credibility in America: What You Can Do About It, Richmond NAACP Annual Meeting, February 10, 1996 (Box 1)
  - 13th Anniversary Prayer Breakfast, February 28, 1996 (Box 1)
  - Flint Automotive Task Force, February 28, 1996 (Box 1)
  - Speech: Faculty Remarks, March 5, 1996 (Box 1)
  - NCA Annual Meeting, March 23-26, 1996 (Box 1)
  - Psi Chi Initiation Banquet, March 29, 1996 (Box 1)
  - University of Arkansas-Pine Bluff Commencement, May 10-12, 1996 (Box 1)
  - Don't Forget to Remember: Advice to the Class of 1996, Commencement, University of Arkansas at Pine Bluff, May 11, 1996 (Box 1)
  - DAS Award-Indiana University Bloomington, June 14-16, 1996 (Box 1)
  - NCA: CIHE Board Meeting, September 16-17, 1996 (Box 1)
  - Rotary, Sarvis Center, September 27, 1996 (Box 1)
  - Transformational Change for the 21st Century, October 13, 1996 (Box 1)
  - Politics of Leadership, Student Leadership Program, October 15, 1996 (Box 1)
  - Have You Fed Any Sheep Today? Mt. Carmel Missionary Baptist Church, October 20, 1996 (Box 1)
  - Genesee County Bar Association, November 18, 1996 (Box 1)
  - Celebrating Community, University of Michigan-Flint, November 19, 1996 (Box 1)
  - Kiwanis Club of Flint Speech, December 12, 1996 (Box 1)
  - Martin Luther King Jr. Day Speech, St. Agnes Catholic Church, January 20, 1997 (Box 1)
  - Flint Community Schools, Lessons Taught/Lessons Learned, February 28, 1997 (Box 1)
  - Christian Man with a Vision, March 23, 1997 (Box 1)
  - Opportunities and Obligations, Mott Community College Commencement, May 3, 1997 (Box 1)
  - Youth Multicultural Conference, May 7-8, 1997 (Box 1)
  - Cream & Crimson Alumni Weekend, June 13-15, 1997 (Box 1)
  - I Believe I Can Fly, June 16, 1997 (Box 1)
  - Neal Marshall Reunion XIII, June 27-29, 1997 (Box 1)
  - Attaining the Dream, Neal Marshall Alumni Association, June 28, 1997 (Box 1)
  - Optimist Speech Idea, July 29, 1997 (Box 1)
  - NBD Bank-Public Affairs Forum, October 20, 1997 (Box 1)
  - Independent Insurance Agents of Genessee County, November 5, 1997 (Box 1)
  - Elements of Successful Models in Achieving Equity and Diversity, November 16, 1997 (Box 1)
  - Golden Leaf Neighborhood Services banquet, University of Michigan-Flint, 1998 (Box 1)
  - Your Court System and Your Video Taping, Committee for Citizen Awareness, January 10, 1998 (Box 1)
  - Michigan Family Resources Coalition, January 14, 1998 (Box 1)
  - President Leadership Seminar, Mott Community College, January 26-30, 1998 (Box 1)
  - Outreach: An Urban University Imperative, February 13, 1998 (Box 1)
  - Diversity Day, Genesee Intermediate School District, February 16, 1998 (Box 1)
  - Natural Resource Conservation Service Black History Month Program, March 2, 1998 (Box 1)
  - Focus Council Executive Committee Remarks, March 12, 1998 (Box 1)
  - 5th Annual Conference, Educational Access, University of Arkansas at Pine Bluff, April 16, 1998 (Box 1)
  - Earlham College Distinguished Lecture Series, April 22, 1998 (Box 1)
  - Spring Finale, Riverfront Hotel, May 2, 1998 (Box 2)
  - Indiana University Bloomington Public Affairs & Government Relations Retreat, June 9, 1998 (Box 2)
  - Indiana University Alumni Executive Council, June 12, 1998 (Box 2)
  - FASE Banquet, September 11, 1998 (Box 2)
  - 20/20: A Vision for Achieving Equity and Excellence, September 16, 1998 (Box 2)
  - Multicultural Student Leadership Institute, September 26, 1998 (Box 2)
  - How I Got Over, 30th Anniversary of Groups, October, 1998 (Box 2)
  - 20/20 Press Conference, October 1, 1998 (Box 2)
  - Why Diversity, ZBT Incident Anniversary, October 14, 1998 (Box 2)
  - Prerequisites for Enhancing Diversity in Higher Education, November 3, 1998 (Box 2)
  - Five Steps to Achieving Your Aspirations, Indianapolis Professional Association, December 12, 1998 (Box 2)
  - 1999 MLK Day Celebration, January 18, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Lessons Taught: Lessons Learned, Indiana University East Black History Celebration, February 25, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Indiana University Student Association Spring Series Events, March 9, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Panelist: The Truth About Affirmative Action, April 14, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Pro & Con Taping, Indiana University Bloomington, April 21, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Cooper Industries Diversity Training, Syracuse, NY, July 11-12, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Hudson Institute, July 13, 1999 (Box 2)
  - FASE Banquet, September 10, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Teaching in a Diverse Context, AI Workshop, September 24, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Indiana University Student Association Fall Retreat, September 25, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Panel Member: Business & Law Society, Indiana University School of Law, October 6, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Purdue Student Services Seminar, October 21, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Why Diversity, Financial Management & Business Symposium, November 3, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Why Diversity, Ed St. John's HESA Class, November 5, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Crichton College Commencement, November 16-19, 1999 (Box 2)
  - C565 Introduction to College Administration, November 30, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Lilly Retention Forum, December 3, 1999 (Box 2)
  - The Unfinished Agenda: The Role of Alpha Men, December 4, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Building Inclusive Community Workshop, Division of Residential Programs & Services, Indiana University Bloomington, January 5, 2000 (Box 2)
  - Prerequisites for Working and Managing in Diversity, Professional Council Forum, Indiana University, January 13, 2000 (Box 2)
  - Deterioration of Black Women, Indiana University Bloomington, February 9, 2000 (Box 2)
  - Main Streaming Diversity Efforts: 20/20 and Beyond, February 19, 2000 (Box 2)
  - Where does one person's rights end and another's begin?, First Baptist Church, Bloomington, February 27, 2000 (Box 2)
  - Beyond Tolerance, Unveiling of Respect Day Poster, February 28, 2000 (Box 2)
  - From Words to Will: Achieving the Diversity We Talk About, March 2, 2000 (Box 2)
  - Building Inclusive Communities, March 27, 2000 (Box 2)
  - Remarks for Plenary Session, NCA Annual Meeting, April 2, 2000 (Box 2)
  - University of Michigan School of Education Commencement, April 29, 2000 (Box 2)
  - Opening Remarks: Improving Diversity: Research Informing Policy, May 10, 2000 (Box 2)
  - Panel Member: NAACP State of Black Education Summit, May 20, 2000 (Box 2)
  - Lessons Taught: Lessons Learned, McNeil High School, May 26, 2000 (Box 2)
  - FACET: Leadership Institute and Diversity in the Curriculum, May 30, 2000 (Box 2)
  - IT: Meeting the Needs of Regional Campuses, June 2, 2000 (Box 2)
  - Panel Member: IUAA Executive Council Meeting, June 16, 2000 (Box 2)
  - Upward Bound Students, IU Bloomington, July 7, 2000 (Box 2)
  - Colloquium for Women, September 15-16, 2000 (Box 2)
  - School of Optometry Advisory Board, IU Bloomington, September 29-30, 2000 (Box 2)
  - EMA Conference, IU Kokomo, November 2, 2000 (Box 2)
  - Student Trustee Search and Screening Committee, November 17, 2000 (Box 2)
  - Don't Let Your Learning Get in the Way of your Education, November 30, 2000 (Box 2)
  - Earlham College Convocation Series, January 9-10, 2001 (Box 2)
  - Introductory Remarks for Julia Carson, February 20, 2001 (Box 2)
  - Serving the Common Good in a Diverse Society, Higher Learning Commission Opening Remarks, April 1, 2001 (Box 2)
  - Serving the Common Good in a Diversity Society, Higher Learning Commission Annual Meeting, April 1, 2001 (Box 2)
  - Introduction of Maya Angelou, IU Bloomington Auditorium, April 11, 2001 (Box 2)
  - Gwen Paulk Memorial Service, April 16, 2001 (Box 2)
  - TRIO Programs, I-MAEOPP, May 7, 2001 (Box 2)
  - NAACP State Conference, May 19, 2001 (Box 2)
  - Indiana Faculty Leadership Institute, May 29, 2001 (Box 2)
  - IU Southeast Leadership Retreat, August 15, 2001 (Box 2)
  - LeaderShape IU 2001 Guest Leader, August 21, 2001 (Box 2)
  - Why Diversity, AI Training, August 22, 2001 (Box 2)
  - Fiscal Officers Training, September 18, 2001 (Box 2)
  - Wayne County NAACP Banquet, September 22, 2001 (Box 2)
  - Advising for Academic Excellence, Bloomington Advisors' Council, September 28, 2001 (Box 2)
  - Prerequisities for Academic Leadership, October 1, 2001 (Box 2)
  - The Diversity Accountability Model, All of One Nation Conference, October 1, 2001 (Box 2)
  - Remarks: Holland Lecture, October 8, 2001 (Box 2)
  - Northwest Neal Marshall Alumni Group, IU Northwest, October 24, 2001 (Box 2)
  - Prerequisites for Diversifying the Academic, October 27, 2001 (Box 2)
  - EMA Conference Luncheon, IU Kokomo, November 1, 2001 (Box 2)
  - Indiana University Climate Changes: A Warning Trend speech, Neal-Marshall Reunion XV, November 2, 2001 (Box 2)
  - Remarks: Conversations on Race Closing Celebration, November 6, 2001 (Box 2)
  - Beyond the Rhetoric: A Time for Action, The Ohio State University, November 8, 2001 (Box 2)
  - Diversity: A Bridge to the Future Conference speech, November 9, 2001 (Box 2)
  - Dan Rives Staff Meeting, November 14, 2001 (Box 2)
  - MEA Coffee Hour; remarks on recruitment and retention of minority students, African American Culture Center, November 16, 2001 (Box 3)
  - Session facilitator: MAP LEADership Seminar Series, December 5, 2001 (Box 3)
  - Crane Memorial Service for Dr. Martin Luther King, January 16, 2002 (Box 3)
  - Neal-Marshall Black Cultural Center Dedication, January 18, 2002 (Box 3)
  - Rashad's Honors Day Speech, March 1, 2002 (Box 3)
  - Indiana Latino/a Student Leadership Conference, March 2, 2002 (Box 3)
  - 20/20 Update to the Bloomington Faculty Council, April 16, 2002 (Box 3)
  - Bloomington Faculty Council Presentation Speech and Handouts, April 16, 2002 (Box 3)
  - Paul Harding High School speech, April 17, 2002 (Box 3)